Great thank you also much for coming I'm
...this is...and liz and from the window shell engineering team
...like to welcome those in the audience are webcast viewers energy channel nine viewers.
So, we help you had a chance to see continuum in the keynote yesterday all the buzz and
everything just making as getty and hearing the feedback from use really wonderful our team
feels just incredibly lucky to be working on what you think is a
gain changing experience for phones we've worked incredibly hard.
To put to pull together and some demos today the your
...to get to see...the first...showing live code.
today we're going to give you an overview of continuum and then some consideration for use developers.
So, I know there's one thing in here that we all share and that's our love for
phones I never it's always at my side.
We sleet nested then we take...to the bathroom their favorite dinner date.
In japan...they
...to create waterproof phones because ninety percent of teens would not take a shower without their phone.
And, phones are very powerful the processing our
of a phone is reveling that of a desktop pc.
But, even with this processing our sometimes...just not enough...are great
when you're on-the-go but the foreign foam form factor can...limiting.
here and excel you can see my reporting spreadsheet and I can panorama and I can see
the details but because of the screen size is difficult to get the whole picture.
And, we've all had times where we had a
...along email or edit a document and we wish we had a...
So, this is why we created continuum,
continuum is part of the windows operating system enables
a windows phone to power-pc like experience for windows apps.
So, you can imagine walking into a dorm.
Or hook home office and docking your windows phone to display
keyboard and mouse.
So, what you see here this is not a pc but the phone is powering both of
these screens?
And, excel here is a windows app that
...scaling for to the screen size and showings adaptive layout.
One of the things that we love is that the phone continue to be a phone so even when
I'm using excel I can still use my phone for other applications for
...for phone calls.
Whatever.
Continuum it allows you to have to apps one-half on your phone one
of unconnected screen both being powered by your phone
windows apps scale beautifully among these screens and when you want to input with then you can use
...mouse or controller app that we designed to be a software touch pad?
So, if you build a windows app it runs on windows mobile and
...designed to adapt and respond to any size in many
case your apps are just going to work and...get the value of this for free.
So, now I'm very...come up and
...through demo this is the first-time ever...showcasing our life code.
Thank you.
Thanks...thanks to all of you in the room and those of you online it's a privilege to be able
to presented today so if you watched the keynote yesterday you saw
...present a simulation of continuum for phone and to be
quite honest with you over the past week has been a couple of days where we thought we might be showing you that same simulation
in here but ...and redman work really hard to put together a
good solid build and we're really excited to share that with you today keep in mind though
this is live code this is a work-in-progress there's some rough edges that you'll see there's some glitches that
I'm sure we'll come up during the demo so keep in mind bear with us a little bit.
Now before I get started.
I've got...of questions online over the past twenty four hours about the accessories
this feature require any specific hardware or accessories in order to enable it and the
answer is no as a matter-of-fact for this presentation what I have here is a wireless setup
them doing and I have a windows phone obviously running windows ten on it I have a
bluetooth keyboard and mouse on that are paired with the phone and I have a mirror
...receiver this is an action tech screaming pro america receiver?
Ok, so, let's get started.
Let's say I get a text message from a colleague.
And, they want to me to update the number in our budget spreadsheet.
So, no, problem I'm actually going to copy that number to the
clipboard because I'll use it later now I have excel on the phone of course.
And, I can go ahead and there's a file.
Not easy when you get fat fingers all right wait a minute let's try that again.
...device.
Actually the area sorry about that
...I weren't ok so this is excel on the phone now
it's universal windows app so it scales down this is a small this is the small-screen the phone form
factor and layout of course but as
...said...is kind of a dens file and be a little bit difficult to work with
this on the phone you much easier work with it on the big-screen...keyboard and mouse.
So, let's go ahead I'm...get to...for you guys let's get connected...my phone here.
By opening up action center clicking our new connect button.
Click that and.
Welcome to continuum analytically sound really cheesy that welcome to the future.
So, this is my phone start screen right it's exactly as I've customizing my apps
...familiar location and it works great with mouse.
Bring my...over here I can scroll up and down.
Can use...clicked customize it there we go into
...the things that I'm used to doing on my phone with start?
Look, at the upper left-hand corner here there's my network strings icon over on the right is
my battery icon in the clock this is my phone and, this is my phone powering
second...but over here if you bring attention to the phone part of the picture
and picture I can go back and there's excel still running there.
Ok, so, let's have a little fun here.
Let's open excel we're going to bring it over to the big-screen simply go to start.
Quick that.
...flows.
Father happen there was excel received a window resize event and reload for the second screen and
look this is excel as I'm used to using in on the universal windows
...on the big-screen.
It looks great it works great with keyboard and mouse.
And, let's see I want to go ahead and make that change so keep
...the charts here I write clicked...a
...in their everything refresh is it works just like excel this is a great thing about
continuum about windows apps is I have one
binary and I can design that to flow in re scale for different form factors
what is one binary across of form factors all right so.
Now I can be I can continue to be productive here at
my keyboard mouse but let's say I'm done working and now I want to
go downstairs and watch a movie on my tv of america receiver connected to the tv
in my living room...I can sit back and my couch and I can stream from my phone but I don't have a
keyboard and have a mouse down there so...mention for that we built is the continuum
comptroller app now if you look at this blue bar across the top of the phone says I'm connected
...says...control go ahead and do that and this is...control
...we're still working on this still work-in-progress here?
But, this operates just like a track pad so I'm
going-to go ahead here and if I if I move my finger around on the screen what you'll see is the
...should move should move I said we're...working on this ...move on the external screen.
I can tap on icons to open
then I can tap on items within applications if I taped in a text field
...application the keyboard on the phone will come up and I can inter text
...that will then be routed directly into the application running on the external screen.
So, last thing I'll
leave you with is let's take that movie watching scenario
...run all the way through and go to open are video app.
And, I have a video and here.
...we, yeah, we just posted this online yesterday let's do that on external screen.
Ok, there we go
...get sound turn down on this joe had his chance to speak yesterday
...great look at this is an http video...really
...external screen...looks awesome and now let's see what I can do on the phone.
...a start.
I might want to check my calendar.
Outlook mail app...the video...external screen is still running if this were a
...video and if you have kids you've probably seen those the videos
...kids like about fifty times so it's great to be able to strain that video check your email.
Now I know what you're thinking and I want to say we've actually we can do this with streaming video
for the web and it's still just as rocks...great.
Art folks that's a little brief overview of continuum thanksgiving.
...great thank you so my studio we did it
...that superfund for all of our team out watching of
...fun to show all right so
continuous a really important featurefor windows ten our vision is to enable
a pc experience for everyone on every screen in.
Develop markets where people have pc's is much more around flexibility
and convenience if you leave your laptop at work or you're just too lazy to bring
You can be confident that you can get your work done if you need to
and this is what we're delivering for windows ten.
Emerging markets like china and india the
smartphones the first and only computing device for many people you can imagine if
...student and you have just one computing device it will be a phone.
And, you know, what likely you also have a tv?
So, now you can imagine taking your windows phone connecting
...existing television adding a
keyboard and mouse and having a pc experience maybe for the first-time.
We know from our research...this is really a game changer
...really impactful when we brought this scenarios to those markets.
And, this is the roadmap for continuum.
So, we talk today about how continuum can light up a
display and keyboard and mouse.
But, we actually do the envision a world where the phone powers many more screens
...experiences where every screen can become a pc.
So, continuum enables a new class of low-cost flexible hardware.
That can be powered by the phone.
So, what you're seeing here this is
not a laptop this is a display and keyboard?
And, there's no processor inside the
phone is powering this device to be just like a laptop.
And, here you can imagine taking away that
does the keyboard and having a tablet there's so many other ideas that we have.
So, what are the other great things about these devices that they can be shared so, for example,
in my household I can be using this device and then my husband can pick it
up and can use his...our and have a
personalize experience with his apps his data his services and my
phone my son can pick it up and use it for homework so we're really,
really excited to talk about how the continuum scenarios might light up your windows apps
and then invite liz to come in and talk about the considerations for use...
Thanks everyone really awesome to be here I'm so happy that are demo actually works for you
moi so, now and take of the rest the time to talk about what
you as developers actually need to think about when developing apps that run on continuum.
So, we have a bunch of developer considerations only about three of them are really integral
to your success and then we have a couple other topics we just want to show
off and get you thinking about but before we talk about those I...make sure everyone's grounded in the
three hardware configurations that will be available in windows ten.
So, the first configuration of the wired...
You could think of someone going home sitting at a desk in front of a monitor keyboard and
mouse to be productive now in this configuration there's a docked serves as a hub for these
four accessories the monitor keyboard mouse and phone the
...mouse are plugged in we are us beat the
doc or they can be paired via bluetooth to the phone itself.
Now the big benefit of this scenario is that because the phone is actually plugged into the
...your phone will be charging while using the external screen.
...get the best performance possible.
Now I know a lot of people prefer wireless configurations
so you can also have the same productivity centric scenario with the wireless
...main difference between this and the previous scenario being that instead of
plugging your phone and you just connect we are cast.
So, our final configuration is a wireless dangle.
You can think of someone going home and lounging back on the couch with friends
and family and instead of using a keyboard and asked to...small-screen we
actually expect people to use the phone with the continuum controller here you can enjoy
videos music photos any other windows...that you want on the big-screen.
The big benefit of this is flexibility you could take your phone
and our any screen on-the-go and navigate with our application.
...the most important thing for us...developer to remember is that users will
interact with your windows apps on big screens with the keyboard and mouse powered by a phone.
All right so the one thing that's really going to help you be successful on continuum is building adaptive apps.
No, I'm not going to go into a bunch of detail on our windows scaling model
and effective pixels but it is integral to your understanding of building adaptive apps.
Megapixels...virtual you a virtual unit of measurements that we use
in windows to give describe the size of any display.
Effective resolution of a device is determined by
combination of the actual theoretical physical pencil pixel density of
the device and theoretical viewing distant that the user...standing from it.
The big benefit of using effective pixels...you is developers can design and build your
ui one-time and we windows system actually does a lot of work on your behalf to make sure that
you I looks great on any screen.
I would make sure that...and reference and sessions on effective pixels after this.
So, developing for continuum really means making sure
your windows app adapt dynamically to any screen from a phone.
In our configurations we really expect to for users to see
...optimize you iphone and big-screen optimized...on the big-screen.
Now when we think about adaptation we think about nthree kind of building principals the first
of which is called fluid ui that flutie why is all about
the building ui elements...effective pixels and positioning
...elements relative to each other and container that...on a screen.
This is kind of the foundation of building adaptive app and if you do this you should get some default
behavior for adaptation on continuum.
So, given a window size change your app should be able to resize to any screen.
You can see that as a screens I shrinks the content in this green actually resize is to better
...space but it's n.
You can also use rapid...controls to reef low and
...content-based on the with that's available you could
wrap text images tiles or any other kind of grid like structure.
So, let's look at a more concrete example.
...this view we have three main ui elements the first one on top is just a
...always spanned one hundred-percent of the with the screen.
Then there's an element in the bottom left that spend third of the screen.
And, element in the bottom right that...two-thirds so this view
is designed with only with percentage base layouts and the content is either
right justified or left justified the container itself or to other ui elements.
This means that when the
...size shrinks this captain adapt really...naturally any screen size.
So, ...do this on your own you should reference the relative panel class this class will help
position ui elements on any screen relative to each other
and container using this class with percentage base layouts and things like
...controls will give you a fundamental scaling experience on any screen.
All right so the secondif you want to do a little bit more work than just that basically
...you can use responsive ui and this is all about revealing and morphing and
...ui at specific snap points.
Now...point is a triggered the you use to actually snap between two different
...layouts for continuum we should just that you use is not point of seven hundred sixty eight
effective pixels this seems kind of arbitrary but it's actually kind of the line between
what devices we consider to be a phone what devices we consider to be larger displays
of not phones so pretty device that's lessons on hundred sixty-eight effective pixels
...user should see phone centric ui...bigger screens large-screen you are.
So, responsive ui is all about using adaptive triggers
...can use adaptive triggers to reveal content...specific snap points.
You can see that as the screen shrinks a
button emerges that's very custom for the phone and only relevant on phones.
You can also reposition new so in this example
as a screen shrinks ui element a and b convince a little bit but
...specific point...to narrow so at this point you are
ailment be actually snaps of the side and moves down below ui element a.
Let's look at the same example so at some point if I screen
...screen a little bit too much what's going to happen is this is
...become...the two columns are going to have weird one-line
text fields so instead of just shrinking it that point it's actually beneficial
for the developer just break off that right-hand bottom ui element and
...along the bottom.
So, let's take a look at an example of using...trigger.
This example...developer wants to show a
wide button on big screens and actually exchange that button for a narrow button on small screens.
We focus on the top developers using the adaptor trigger of minimum window
wits to say okay if the screen is greater than seven hundred sixty
...effective pixels show wide button.
And, if it's less than seven hundred sixty a pixels show narrow buttoned optimized for the phone.
So, this adaptive...the...triggers can be used in many ways and with many different
types of triggers this is an example of using minimum window width but you
can also imagine using input type or device family or some other custom trigger.
finally if you really want to optimize your application for any screen you can use...ui.
Tiller ui is reallytiller utilizes the same adaptive triggers we
just discussed but more complex scenarios.
We generally expect developers really want to tailor experience to actually tear down and
reconstruct their app either with new views or new navigation models across screen sizes.
For example, you can replace controls are ui elements as a screen at
a specifics that point in this example the big-screen view is pretty
desktop centric you can think about it as being pretty dense and...a keyboard and
...navigate but below sets that point you really want to optimize for touch on a phone or tablet
...actually...themselves that by...into a scrollable list.
You can also just re architect the entire navigation model and
...of your application this example on the big-screen application has a two-column
view column with a list...call with a reading...and as a screen
shrinks that actually switches to a single column view to optimize for screen size.
As I said you can use what are the exact same adaptive triggers to build
...ui just a growing complexity.
Right so I'm actually going to switch over and show you guys a couple of adaptive apps
...action hopefully we will have some demoing abilities again.
Ok, so, I'm actually...take a look at the weather
...whether app is a really good example of an application that uses vary basic fluid
...principles to make sure that they adapt to any screen size so here you can see that
...two degrees I'm kind...not outside there's a weekly preview of the
whether some charts and then details.
...going-to go ahead and move this app to the big-screen.
Lovely
okay so you can see that actually re flows really nicely on the big-screen pretty sweet.
So, I can show you guys side-by-side actually going to pull
up another phone and with the weather app already on it so I can show you what's going on.
So, if you look at these two devices the...looks essentially the same and
it appears to be the same-size on both screens.
Appears to be the same-size because
developers use effective pixels to actually build ui elements and the fonts
so the system on their behalf does work to make sure that...I looks great across all screens.
They do a lot of good stuff with reciting ui elements so they resize this window where they
so that on a big-screen you can see more days saved eight or ten on the small-screen you have to scroll.
Identify navigate...details list go over here.
You can see that on the phone it's just a simple list of details but on the big-screen where the
screens much wider they actually
...those details to be...details horizontally using a rapid style control.
Let's take a look at a couple more apps hopeful up outlook mail.
Outlook mail as a good example of an app that actually changes
...navigation model as specific snap point.
Reminder the forum showing is not the phone powering external screen
...another...I'm just using...I can show you guys the app side-by-side.
Lovely so perfect.
So, this is alec on the big-screen very similar
be identical to what you would see on desktop so you can see on the phone outlook has this single
column view where they actually just have either the reading list may lists
...go in and will...just that mail?
You can see on the big-screen...have that same mail open it actually raf...and you can see the three
column view so outlook uses specific
stat points determine when they should show one versus...views.
For one must demo switch over
to outlook calendar within outlook hopefully this work for us.
...calendar on the phone is really optimized for just checking
...what you're doing today or what you're doing next...kind of assume people are on-the-go and just want to see with the next appointment
is so here I basically can either look at my gender I can look at my day?
Now on the big-screen they actually have well, hang on...again.
Bug...on the big-screen...available.
They theoretical make available the month-to-month few weeks view
...because they really want you to be able to take advantage of that big-screen and the best way possible.
So, we'll go ahead and switch back over to that.
Great so now
...about building adaptive apps let's talk about the different ways that you can
package windows apps such that they work well...continuum.
If you will need adaptive windows app that runs on windows mobile your apple have some default behavior
on continuum.
Now there's three main ways that you can package...such that it works.
The best thing you can do is just building universal windows up with a universal windows
...package.
If you do this we're generally assuming that you're building and app that's going to adapt across all screens
and device families so you're already doing everything you need to do to work on continuum
rapture just work.
The...that I showed is a really good example of nap that
...universal up and it just works
...our scenario they had no idea continuum was even a feature when they were building...application.
Second type of...package
that compatible continuum is mobile only apps so we know a lot of developers
...mobile only developers and they really focused on the phone and
...phone app and that's totally fine now the thing that we do ask you
to do...that you've built your the...your mobile apps with fluid responsive and
tailored ui such that they actually do have some dynamic...lab.
So, if you want to do a little bit of work you can use...adaptive principles to further optimize
...optimizations are things you have to do anyway just to make sure that when the orientation of a phone
changes that...in the right way so the benefit you both on the phone and on continuum.
Now if you discover that you really want to optimize...mobile app for continuum you might
as well just think about building universal windows up because you're already doing a lot of work to optimize
...big-screen views and they that work could be seen across all windows device families.
let's take a look at a couple of mobile only windows absentee what they look like on the big-screen.
And, switch over to my phone.
Leveling or it's almost phone I have the photos application and this is
a mobile only
...not universal windows application and you can see here that I have my
photos they look leveling so I'm going-to go ahead and move this over the big-screen.
Sewers lovely so.
You can see here that the photos that actually has
...use rapid style controls to ensure that the photos...learn nicely
and both orientations on the phone and network paid off on the big-screen because the apps now
...properly to that screen with as well.
So, I can also go ahead and open app here just for fun
...photo see full-screen image we're having one of those I hope you guys are too.
Ok, so, now...show you one more apt to actually did
...little a couple of very small tweaks that make a big difference on the big-screen.
So, file scores another
mobile only application and it's basically there's two options you can see my
...documents or I can see all the documents on this device this is very
similar kind of information I would...on the desktop so I'm going-to go ahead and move this the big-screen as well.
Bubbling so ...moves the folders actually just use
a similar rapid style control so they re for nicely to the big-screen.
Now the thing I want to point out is that on the phone the
file explore actually had a tab menu that was hiding that recent and this device those
reason and this device options...big-screen
they ops just leave this open permanently which is much nicer for desktop...user.
Kill switch back to slides.
So, we've talked about.
Developers have universe what packages developers...mobile only app packages
...talk about developers who have both
mobile separate but both mobile and pc app packages
now but default we won't have any concept of your pc...package on continuum
...won't even be on the phone so generally if you do no work for continuum what is
see your mobile experience on the big-screen just as if you had a mobile...application.
Now if you want to do a little bit more work and leverage the work you've done
...the desktop it's up to...actually pull assets
or views from your pc application in your mobile app package and do the work to switch between them?
He's really simple example basically you could think of it and
...logic as hey if the screen sizes smaller than a phone use my phone view if you are pull
your pc viewing you can use that pc wvu on large screens.
The obviously this is very simplistic and you probably would...do things like savior
...states and make sure your refreshing content correctly whenever you switch views.
So,...phone and look at another example of an example of what this could look like.
All right so here have microsoft word on the phone you can see I have my...documents.
Thanks...samoa.
I have my word document I could edit here if I wanted to and
the main difference between office on the phone and office on the big-screen...
over the controls so instead of the traditional desktop ribbon that everyone's used
to I can actually use this bottom control to change things like my fonts my
...insert images or do anything else this control
is really optimized for touch and thumbs and doing things on the phone so I
want actually move word over to the big-screen?
...offices on the big-screen so, what office...between
screens is basically the first thing happens is office get the window resize events and
when it gets out events they have to make a decision if they're going to keep showing the phone new or if they're
going to actually exchange...those asked that those assets with the more desktop friendly
ui so if they decide actually exchange those than they need to tear down
...they're all controls save state and reconstruct
...with the new controls just like they did here?
The offices really good example of an app that uses both
tailored ui and vary basic resize principles the document itself
actually just resize is to some percentage based on screen width there's nothing really fancy happening with it.
So, we'll go back to this slide please.
All right so how do you test your applications on continuum so,
generally we expect that your applications will respond and adapts given only when
a resize events and knowing and based on the width of the screen
...on so really what you could do is just tested on
the desktop because if you resize...window on a desktop then you'll see
you'll get exactly the same events the same things will happen as if it was moving between
...continuum if your successful when you resize a window on desktop you should be successful in
our scenario now this is a bit nuance obviously if you're
using more complex triggers you'd have to developed has tocs to actually tester application.
Ok, so, let's talk a little bit about scaling by scaling I mean how do you make sure that
you have the right assets to make your...pixel perfect on any given screen.
The reason this...integral to your success...is because of
our phones today have very high resolutions so any assets the provided for the
phone will actually look pretty good across any display size also driving a detail.
So, as a developer you need to think about...up-scale to the big-screen.
Again, a background effective pixels in the scaling model as key to truly understanding this.
You should...sessions.
everyone does device every device in the windows platforms associated with a specific scale.
And, this scale is derived from the effective resolution of the device
...remember the effective resolution is computed from a combination of the physical
...pixel density...theoretical viewing distance of...device.
So, in our scenario most common kind of scale going to be a
full have a scale about three hundred monitor typically has a scale of one hundred
...television-type we have a...hundred-fifty.
So, you can see that there's not really necessarily a direct
core not does not necessarily direct correlation between screen size
...form factor and scale it really does depend on that
physical resolution and the theoretical viewing distance or how far experience from the user?
And, also these skills are used by the resource management system
...management system basically looked at all the assets you provided
...package...the right once for any screen.
Let's take a look at how scales working continuum.
As I said a...is probably usually about two hundred four hundred three hundred a good number.
And, the actual screen...the...into will typically have a scale between one hundred...fifty.
Default only scale...for the phone will actually be deployed
...phone even if you made more assets available in your...package it first
resource management system tries to minimize the number of assets that go on any given device but also
optimized for whatever screens are actually
...device so if the phone has a scale factor of three hundred
then by default only scale three hundred assets will ever be deployed that device.
Yeah, that's all problematic at first because monitors really want to
...a...one hundred or scale one fifty.
It at first connection or quite a full you kind of get this experience where such as say three hundred
sorry where the phone and the big-screen are both scale three hundred?
But, if you do work to make assets available in your
...package for say scale one hundred and scale one fifty and the resource management system washer
do all of the work for you to make sure that those correct assets wind up on the right screen at
the right time.
You don't have to do anything but provide the assets for it.
And, all note to save space if the user doesn't...the screen within thirty days
...those assets will be removed from the phone and re downloaded if needed.
if you don't provide assets you basically run the risk of your app of your assets not scaling frankly are
not being pixel perfect on...screen.
the worst-case scenario for continuum is that your asked redone scaled we can basically
...because we know our phones have very high-resolution screens and all the
...and tv's that your connecting to what most likely be either the same
resolution or lower-resolution.
So, whenever...down...the system is essentially taking one of the high-resolution images you provided
for the phone and scale it down to the lower-resolution of the connected monitor or tv.
when this happens the icons basically become not pixel perfect they're
compressed but reality they won't really look that bad the average person probably
can't really tell the difference between this compressed image and the pixel perfect image?
So, that's why it's not really integral to your success...our scenario.
But, in case you do...pixel perfect here's how you actually go about adding and referencing scaling
resources...asking resources in one of two ways first.
You can add new assets to an...folder in your absolution you add them
...the nomenclature of name dot scaled as
xxx whatever scale you're using you can just throw all of your assets in this one folder and
if you use this nomenclature the system will find the right...right time and put them on the right screens.
You can also have skills specific folders so rather than paying all your assets in one
folder
you can actually just put individual are the same set of assets and different scaling folders
and again the system will do the right thing to grab the right once on the right screens.
I will know that you can actually mix and match this organization system...skill folders
...assets folder and the system hunt the role of them.
You can reference resources with url living
...xxx again the system knows what...looking for knows how to find it
An example.
An image tag and...look something like this.
And, this is really your referencing the logo image that in your asset folder and based on whatever
screener on the system will go and find the best the best scaled image for that screen.
Right so we want to leave you with one final scenario.
You developers have the ability to take advantage of both screens in
the scenarios simultaneously there's a handful of api for this and,
there's actually a session later this evening called screen...that you should tend if you're interested in less.
But, the voltage create
...essentially allow you to take advantage about the phone natural display simultaneously
for basically creating any sort of robust multi-stream experience you want.
Going to highlight to api here that work really well continuum again I encourage you to go to their session.
The first api that's available...the cast dpi.
This api allows you to take a media
elements from your application on the phone and put it on the external screen.
Now what's happening we call this api...the system is to operating a
wvu on that screen on your behalf taking your media elements and just putting it there.
This is the easiest thing for you to do as a developer if you have a media app and,
just want get media on external screen.
Now if you're not
a media developer you can use the projection manager api this will allow you to create
to completely customized views...on the phone
one on the big-screen and basically do whatever you want to do with those views note that if you
use this api you have to remember that you are the only form of control the user...on
...screen so whatever view you have on your phone needs to be able to provide input to
the external screen yes we'll have our continuum comptroller but we don't the user to have to leave your
apt navigate what...ve put out on...screen.
So, let's take a look at how you actually go about using...manager at a high-level
so the first thing you do is just start by checking whether or not there's even a device
connected if there's not you'd have to handle it as a single screen but if there is.
You can go ahead and create the view that you want to put both on the external screen.
And, on the phone.
...point and then once of
...created you-can call production manager dot start production asic to show your new
just your needed wvu on the display and then once you're done with
...session you-can call stop rejection is inc.
...as well and...your apple returned the screen that originated on.
All right so one last demo for you guys hopefully it will be just a successful before
...which are the phone rates so here I have
historically whenever people have done slide shows from their phones they...of the state where the
...shows actually mirrored across the to screens...my slide their ansi my slides here so
powerpoint actually utilized to projection manager in a new...windows phone go ahead and start my presentation.
Awesome so now you can see that instead of seeing the myriad thing where I see the
...on the screens actually see not only the
slides on my phone but also my notes and the...
I can really easily just slide between these...new going back because obviously that animation.
So, you guys
...can really easily go through here you can see that the animations are crisp and clean.
It looks great on the big-screen and my notes are readily available for me on the phone.
...expert biochemistry moi.
All right so I'm...go ahead and finish up the presentation from my
phone calls already connected with just some calls...action for you guys...developers.
Now...mingled action is just that we really are asking you to build
...apps or optimize your mobile apps for continuum if you are ready or don't want to
...universal up?
Now there's a couple ways you can optimize are mobile applications
...you can just use the adaptive principles we discussed to make sure your ui
...nicely to any screen or...if you have pcs
...you can actually do the work to pull those assets and your mobile app package.
Once you actually have not package you should validate that you I looks good on the small-screen
and the big-screen we don't really care how you implement it how you switch what shows
on each screen...you just be able to interact with it and enjoy their experience.
Also make sure it works with...
mouse as that will be supported not only on continuum but on phones in general now.
Now if you want to be picture-perfect you should also think about including additional scaling
asses for the external screen for continuum there's really two scales
that are important scale one hundred scale one fifty for the monitors and tvs.
And, finally if you want already have applicable applications
...leverage these multi screen api...actually create robust multi...experiences.
we just wanted to say thank you so much for coming we are just super excited about continuum and the
scenarios...it's going to drive in the
...we will be here for questions afterwards and
...thank you very much...